{
  "dars1": [
    { "front": "a", "back": "bir" },
    { "front": "about", "back": "haqida" },
    { "front": "add", "back": "qo‘shmoq" },
    { "front": "afternoon", "back": "peshin" },
    { "front": "again", "back": "yana" },
    { "front": "Alex", "back": "Alek" },
    { "front": "Alice", "back": "Elis" },
    { "front": "alien", "back": "begona" },
    { "front": "alphabet", "back": "alfavit" },
    { "front": "an", "back": "bir" },
    { "front": "and", "back": "va" },
    { "front": "angry", "back": "g‘azablangan" },
    { "front": "animal", "back": "hayvon" },
    { "front": "Ann", "back": "Ann" },
    { "front": "answer", "back": "javob" },
    { "front": "apartment", "back": "kvartira" },
    { "front": "apple", "back": "olma" },
    { "front": "arm", "back": "qo‘l" },
    { "front": "artist", "back": "san'atkor" },
    { "front": "ask", "back": "so‘ramoq" },
    { "front": "at", "back": "da" },
    { "front": "away", "back": "uzoq" },
    { "front": "baby", "back": "bola" },
    { "front": "back", "back": "orqa" },
    { "front": "bad", "back": "yomon" },
    { "front": "bag", "back": "sumka" },
    { "front": "ball", "back": "top" },
    { "front": "banana", "back": "banan" },
    { "front": "band", "back": "guruҳ" },
    { "front": "bank", "back": "bank" },
    { "front": "bar", "back": "bar" },
    { "front": "base", "back": "asos" },
    { "front": "basket", "back": "savatcha" },
    { "front": "bath", "back": "vanna" },
    { "front": "be", "back": "bo‘lmoq" },
    { "front": "beach", "back": "sohil" },
    { "front": "beautiful", "back": "chiroyli" },
    { "front": "bed", "back": "karavot" },
    { "front": "before", "back": "oldin" },
    { "front": "begin", "back": "boshlamoq" },
    { "front": "behind", "back": "ortida" },
    { "front": "believe", "back": "ishonmoq" },
    { "front": "below", "back": "pastda" },
    { "front": "beside", "back": "yonida" },
    { "front": "between", "back": "orasida" },
    { "front": "big", "back": "katta" },
    { "front": "bird", "back": "qush" }
  ],
  "dars2": [
    { "front": "biscuit", "back": "pechene" },
    { "front": "book", "back": "kitob" },
    { "front": "boot", "back": "poyabzal" },
    { "front": "bottle", "back": "shisha" },
    { "front": "box", "back": "quti" },
    { "front": "boy", "back": "o‘g‘il bola" },
    { "front": "bread", "back": "non" },
    { "front": "brother", "back": "aka" },
    { "front": "bus", "back": "avtobus" },
    { "front": "but", "back": "lekin" },
    { "front": "buy", "back": "sotib olmoq" },
    { "front": "by", "back": "tomonidan" },
    { "front": "cake", "back": "kek" },
    { "front": "call", "back": "chaqirmoq" },
    { "front": "camera", "back": "kamera" },
    { "front": "can", "back": "qila olmoq" },
    { "front": "capital", "back": "poytaxt" },
    { "front": "car", "back": "avtomobil" },
    { "front": "card", "back": "kartochka" },
    { "front": "cat", "back": "mushuk" },
    { "front": "ceiling", "back": "shift" },
    { "front": "center", "back": "markaz" },
    { "front": "change", "back": "o‘zgartirmoq" },
    { "front": "cheap", "back": "arzon" },
    { "front": "child", "back": "bola" },
    { "front": "church", "back": "cherkov" },
    { "front": "city", "back": "shahar" },
    { "front": "class", "back": "sinf" },
    { "front": "clean", "back": "toza" },
    { "front": "clock", "back": "soat" },
    { "front": "close", "back": "yaqin" },
    { "front": "clothes", "back": "kiyim" },
    { "front": "cloud", "back": "bulut" },
    { "front": "coffee", "back": "kofe" },
    { "front": "cold", "back": "sovuq" },
    { "front": "come", "back": "kelmoq" },
    { "front": "computer", "back": "kompyuter" },
    { "front": "cousin", "back": "jiyan" },
    { "front": "cup", "back": "chashka" },
    { "front": "dance", "back": "raqs" },
    { "front": "day", "back": "kun" },
    { "front": "desk", "back": "stol" },
    { "front": "dog", "back": "it" },
    { "front": "doll", "back": "qushcha" },
    { "front": "door", "back": "eshik" },
    { "front": "down", "back": "pastga" },
    { "front": "drink", "back": "ichmoq" },
    { "front": "drive", "back": "haydamoq" }
  ], "dars3":
[
{ "front": "eat", "back": "yemoq" },
{ "front": "egg", "back": "tuxum" },
{ "front": "elephant", "back": "fil" },
{ "front": "end", "back": "oxiri" },
{ "front": "enjoy", "back": "yoqmoq" },
{ "front": "enter", "back": "kirish" },
{ "front": "evening", "back": "kechqurun" },
{ "front": "example", "back": "misol" },
{ "front": "eye", "back": "ko‘z" },
{ "front": "family", "back": "oilaviy" },
{ "front": "father", "back": "ota" },
{ "front": "few", "back": "oz" },
{ "front": "find", "back": "topmoq" },
{ "front": "finish", "back": "tamomlamoq" },
{ "front": "fish", "back": "balik" },
{ "front": "flat", "back": "tekis" },
{ "front": "flower", "back": "gul" },
{ "front": "follow", "back": "ergashmoq" },
{ "front": "food", "back": "taom" },
{ "front": "for", "back": "uchun" },
{ "front": "friend", "back": "do‘st" },
{ "front": "from", "back": "dan" },
{ "front": "fun", "back": "qiziqarli" },
{ "front": "game", "back": "o‘yin" },
{ "front": "garden", "back": "bog‘" },
{ "front": "get", "back": "olmoq" },
{ "front": "give", "back": "bermoq" },
{ "front": "go", "back": "borish" },
{ "front": "good", "back": "yaxshi" },
{ "front": "grandfather", "back": "bobom" },
{ "front": "grandmother", "back": "buvi" },
{ "front": "green", "back": "yashil" },
{ "front": "guitar", "back": "g‘itar" },
{ "front": "hair", "back": "soch" },
{ "front": "hand", "back": "qo‘l" },
{ "front": "happy", "back": "baxtli" },
{ "front": "have", "back": "ega bo‘lmoq" },
{ "front": "head", "back": "bosh" },
{ "front": "hello", "back": "salom" },
{ "front": "help", "back": "yordam" },
{ "front": "here", "back": "bu yerda" },
{ "front": "home", "back": "uy" },
{ "front": "house", "back": "uy" },
{ "front": "how", "back": "qanday" },
{ "front": "hungry", "back": "och" },
{ "front": "I", "back": "men" },
{ "front": "ice", "back": "muz" }
],
"dars4":
[
{ "front": "if", "back": "agar" },
{ "front": "important", "back": "muqim" },
{ "front": "in", "back": "ichida" },
{ "front": "information", "back": "ma'lumot" },
{ "front": "inside", "back": "ichida" },
{ "front": "interested", "back": "qiziqqan" },
{ "front": "job", "back": "ish" },
{ "front": "journey", "back": "sayohat" },
{ "front": "juice", "back": "sharbat" },
{ "front": "jump", "back": "sakramoq" },
{ "front": "juice", "back": "sharbat" },
{ "front": "kangaroo", "back": "kenguru" },
{ "front": "key", "back": "kalit" },
{ "front": "kind", "back": "xushmuomala" },
{ "front": "kitchen", "back": "oshxona" },
{ "front": "know", "back": "bilmoq" },
{ "front": "large", "back": "katta" },
{ "front": "last", "back": "oxirgi" },
{ "front": "later", "back": "keyinroq" },
{ "front": "laugh", "back": "kulmoq" },
{ "front": "lazy", "back": "temir" },
{ "front": "learn", "back": "o‘rganmoq" },
{ "front": "left", "back": "chap" },
{ "front": "let", "back": "ruxsat bermoq" },
{ "front": "library", "back": "kutubxona" },
{ "front": "listen", "back": "tinglamoq" },
{ "front": "little", "back": "kichik" },
{ "front": "live", "back": "yashamoq" },
{ "front": "love", "back": "sevmoq" },
{ "front": "man", "back": "erkak" },
{ "front": "many", "back": "ko‘p" },
{ "front": "market", "back": "bozor" },
{ "front": "more", "back": "ko‘proq" },
{ "front": "mother", "back": "ona" },
{ "front": "move", "back": "harakat qilmoq" },
{ "front": "movie", "back": "kino" },
{ "front": "much", "back": "ko‘p" },
{ "front": "music", "back": "musiqa" },
{ "front": "name", "back": "ism" },
{ "front": "near", "back": "yaqin" },
{ "front": "nice", "back": "yoqimli" },
{ "front": "night", "back": "kecha" },
{ "front": "no", "back": "yo‘q" },
{ "front": "not", "back": "emas" },
{ "front": "now", "back": "hozir" },
{ "front": "office", "back": "ofis" },
{ "front": "on", "back": "ustida" }
],

"dars5":
[
{ "front": "open", "back": "ochmoq" },
{ "front": "orange", "back": "apelsin" },
{ "front": "over", "back": "ustidan" },
{ "front": "people", "back": "odamlar" },
{ "front": "pet", "back": "uy hayvoni" },
{ "front": "play", "back": "o‘ynamoq" },
{ "front": "please", "back": "iltimos" },
{ "front": "pool", "back": "basseyn" },
{ "front": "project", "back": "loyiha" },
{ "front": "push", "back": "tortmoq" },
{ "front": "question", "back": "savol" },
{ "front": "quiet", "back": "jim" },
{ "front": "rain", "back": "yomg‘ir" },
{ "front": "read", "back": "o‘qimoq" },
{ "front": "red", "back": "qizil" },
{ "front": "restaurant", "back": "restoran" },
{ "front": "ride", "back": "minmoq" },
{ "front": "right", "back": "to‘g‘ri" },
{ "front": "room", "back": "xona" },
{ "front": "run", "back": "yugurmoq" },
{ "front": "school", "back": "maktab" },
{ "front": "see", "back": "ko‘rmoq" },
{ "front": "sell", "back": "sotmoq" },
{ "front": "short", "back": "qisqa" },
{ "front": "shut", "back": "yopmoq" },
{ "front": "sing", "back": "kuylamoq" },
{ "front": "sit", "back": "otirmoq" },
{ "front": "sleep", "back": "uxlamoq" },
{ "front": "small", "back": "kichik" },
{ "front": "snow", "back": "qarag‘ay" },
{ "front": "some", "back": "ba'zi" },
{ "front": "song", "back": "qo‘shiqlar" },
{ "front": "start", "back": "boshlamoq" },
{ "front": "stop", "back": "to‘xtamoq" },
{ "front": "store", "back": "do‘kon" },
{ "front": "study", "back": "o‘qish" },
{ "front": "sun", "back": "quyosh" },
{ "front": "table", "back": "stol" },
{ "front": "take", "back": "olmoq" },
{ "front": "tea", "back": "choy" },
{ "front": "thank", "back": "rahmat" },
{ "front": "them", "back": "ular" }
]
}
